<resources>
    <string name="app_name">City Tour 2.0</string>
    <string name="open">open</string>
    <string name="close">close</string>
    <string name="home">Home</string>
    <string name="general_info">General Info</string>
    <string name="demography">Demography</string>
    <string name="destination">Destination</string>
    <string name="how_to_reach">How To Reach</string>
    <string name="about_bihar">About Bihar</string>
    <string name="developer">Developer</string>
    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="hello_blank_fragment">Hello blank fragment</string>
    <string name="about_bhagalpur">
        Bhagalpur is a city of historical importance on the southern banks of the river Ganges in
        the Indian state of Bihar. It is the 3rd largest city of Bihar and also the headquarters
        of Bhagalpur district and Bhagalpur division. Known as Silk City, it is a major educational,
        commercial, and political centre, and listed for development under the Smart City program
        a joint venture between Government and industry. The Gangetic plains surrounding
        the city are very fertile and the main crops include rice, wheat, maize, barley, and oilseeds.
        The river is home to the Gangetic dolphin, the National Aquatic Animal of India,
        and the Vikramshila Gangetic Dolphin Sanctuary is established near the town.
    </string>

    <string name="coordinates">Coordinates</string>
    <string name="_25_15_n_87_0_e">25°15′N 87°0′E</string>
    <string name="country">Country</string>
    <string name="india">India</string>
    <string name="state">State</string>
    <string name="bihar">Bihar</string>
    <string name="district">District</string>
    <string name="bhagalpur">Bhagalpur</string>
    <string name="urban_agglomeration">Urban Agglomeration</string>
    <string name="municipal_corporation">Municipal Corporation</string>
    <string name="bhagalpur_municipal_corporation">Bhagalpur Municipal Corporation</string>
    <string name="area_total">Area Total</string>
    <string name="_342_km2_132_sq_mi">342 km2 (132 sq mi)</string>
    <string name="area_rank">Area Rank</string>
    <string name="_2nd_in_bihar">2nd(in Bihar)</string>
    <string name="population">Population</string>
    <string name="_4_10_210">4,10,210</string>
    <string name="postal_index_number">Postal Index Number</string>
    <string name="_812001_81xxxx">812001-81XXXX</string>
    <string name="std_code">STD Code</string>
    <string name="_0641">0641</string>
    <string name="vehicle_registration">Vehicle Registration</string>
    <string name="br_10">BR-10</string>
    <string name="website">Website</string>
    <string name="bhagalpur_bih_nic_in">bhagalpur.bih.nic.in</string>

    <string name="demography_fragment">
        As of the 2011 India census, the Bhagalpur Urban Agglomeration has a population of 410,210,
        of which 218,284 were males and 191,926 were females. It is the 3rd largest city in Bihar
        in terms of urban population. the total population in the age group of 0 to 6 years is 55,898.
        The total number of literates are 286,125, with 160,720 males and 125,405 females.
        The effective literacy rate of 7+ population is 80.76%, of which while
        the male literacy rate is 84.95% with women at 75.95%.
    </string>

    <string name="how_to_reach_fragment">
        Bhagalpur is well connected with other part of country by roads and trains.
        Railways: The Bhagalpur Junction railway station, is connected to most of the
        major cities in India by the railway network, which lies in between Howrah Kiul
        loop-line which serves Bhagalpur with numerous number of trains. It is the 3rd
        busiest line in Bihar. About 100 pairs of Express and 40 pairs of
        passenger train pass through this line. Bhagalpur is A1 grade Railway station.
        It is the highest revenue generator in the Malda Rail Division. It
        is the third major railway station in Eastern Railway after Howrah and Sealdah.
        Bhagalpur is well connected to Delhi, Mumbai, Kolkata, Bangalore, Ajmer, Kanpur,
        Patna, Guwahati, Surat, Jammu Tawi, Munger, Gaya and other cities.
        North Bhagalpur is served by the Barauni- Katihar section of the ECR/NFR.
        Narainpur, Thana Bihpur, Naugachhia and Katareah railway stations lie on this line.
    </string>

    <string name="about_bihar_fragment">
        Bihar (/bɪˈhɑːr/; Hindi pronunciation: [bɪˈɦaːr] (About this soundlisten)) is a state in eastern India.
        It is the third-largest state by population and twelfth-largest by territory,
        with an area of 94,163 km2 (36,357 sq mi). It is contiguous with Uttar Pradesh to its west,
        Nepal to the north, the northern part of West Bengal to the east, and with Jharkhand to the south.
        The Bihar plain is split by the river Ganges, which flows from west to east. Three main cultural
        regions converge in the state: Magadh, Mithila, and Bhojpur. In ancient and classical India,
        the area that is now Bihar was considered a centre of power, learning, and culture. From Magadha
        arose India\'s first empire, the Maurya empire, as well as one of the world\'s most widely
        adhered-to religions: Buddhism. Magadha empires, notably under the Maurya
        and Gupta dynasties, unified large parts of South Asia under a central rule.
        Another region of Bihar is Mithila which was an early centre of learning and the centre of the Videha kingdom.
    </string>


    <string name="vikramshila_name">Ruins of Vikramshila</string>
    <string name="vikramshila">
        Ruins of Vikramshila:","The royal university of Vikramsila, 38 km from Bhagalpur ranks next
        to Nalanda and owes its origin to Dharmapala (770-810 A.D.), the devout Pala king who loved
        to call himself Paramasaugata (chief worshipper of the Buddha)and was a great patron of Mahayana
        Buddhism.Dharmapala was impressed by two things which prompted him to establish Vikramsila university.
        Firstly, the rocky hillock anchored around the confluence of Kosi and Ganga at Vateshwarasthan
        was not only a scenic attraction but a popular tantric site as evident from the presence of a
        Kali temple (instead of Parvati’s) in front of Shiva temple, besides various other caves and
        rock cut sculptures dating back to the 6\\7th century A.D. Secondly, the place was
        with pilgrimage due to Uttarbahini which drew large crowds during Varsavardhana.
        Unlike Nalanda, sources of information on Vikramsila is confined to Tibetan texts and
        they make us believe that Dharmapala in his earlier birth was an accomplished acharya,
        Kampilya, who had attained siddhi or perfection in Mahayana mudra mysticism here and
        was determined to build a monastery one day.
    </string>
    <string name="dolphin_name">Vikramshila Gangetic Dolphin Sanctuary</string>
    <string name="dolphin">
        Vikramshila Gangetic Dolphin Sanctuary is located in Bhagalpur District of Bihar, India.
        The sanctuary is a 60 km stretch of the Ganges River from Sultanganj to Kahalgaon in Bhagalpur District.
        Designated in 1991, it is protected area for the endangered Gangetic dolphins in Asia.
        Once found in abundance, only a few hundred remain, of which half are found here.
        The Gangetic dolphins have been declared as the national aquatic animal of India.
        This decision was taken in the first meeting of the National Ganga River Basin Authority (NGRBA)
        chaired by Prime Minister Dr. Manmohan Singh on Monday, 5 October 2009
        Major attractions are the Ganges river dolphins (known as Soons by Locals)
        which are classified as endangered on the 2006 IUCN Red List of Threatened Species and included in Schedule-I
        of the Indian Wildlife Protection Act, 1972. The sanctuary also contains rich diversity
        of other threatened aquatic wildlife, including the Indian smooth-coated otter (Lutrogale perspicillata),
        gharial (Gavialis gangeticus), a variety of freshwater turtles, and 135 species of waterfowl.
    </string>
    <string name="mandar_name">Mandar Hill</string>
    <string name="mandar">
        Mandar Hills (50 km), steeped in legend and laced with landscape of extraordinary splendour
        exposes the 800 feet high granite hill. Mandar is associated with amritmanthana which suggests
        that the hill was used by the gods to churn the ocean to procure amrit. The serpent,
        Basukinaga offered to serve as the rope and has left behind an impression of the coil on the granite hill.
        It is believed that panchjanya, the conch shell used in Mahabharat War was discovered here in the Sank kund.
        The puranas refer to various sacred places on the hill which is also believed to be the abode of
        Vishnu under the title of Madhusudana or the destroyer of a demon called Madhu who
        was killed by Vishnu and then covered by the Mandar hill. Kalidasa\’s kumarasamahava
        refers to foot marks of Vishnu on the slopes of Mandar.The hill is replete with relics of bygone ages.
        Besides inscriptions and statues there are numerous rock cut sculptures depicting
        various Brahmanical images. The hill is equally revered by the Jains who
        believe that their 12th Tirthankara attained nirvana here on the summit of the hill.
    </string>
    <string name="jain_name">Shri Champapur Digamber Jain Siddha Kshetra</string>
    <string name="jain">
        Shri Champapur Digamber Jain Siddha Kshetra is an Siddha Kshetra (Place of Salvation).
        It is quite an ancient and historic Teerth Kshetra. Shri Champapur Digamber Jain Siddha
        Kshetra is located at village Nathnagar, District Bhagalpur Bihar. By road it is 3.5 km
        away from Bhagalpur, 270 Km. Patna. Champapur is the only \‘Panch Kalyanaka Kshetra\’
        in the world which is related to Panch Kalyanaka: – \“(i) Garbha, (ii) Janma, (iii) Tapa,
        (iv) Gyan and (v) Moksha\” 12th Tirthankara Bhagwan Vasupujya (The first ascetic saint).
    </string>
    <string name="kuppaghat_name">Maharshi Mehi Aashram, Kuppaghat</string>
    <string name="kuppaghat">
        Lord Sadguru Maharshi Mehi Paramhansji Maharaj was a Sant in the link of Sants like
        Kabir and Nanak. He had attained perfection and was a God-realized Soul.
        His spirit-force was ever absorbed in the Logos and He was endowed with all the marks of a Sant.
    </string>
    <string name="garur_name">Garuda Sanctuary</string>
    <string name="garur">
        World\'s Second Largest Rescue and Rehabilitation Area for Garuda is Bhagalpur. In Indian mythology,
        Garuda is considered the vahana or carrier of the god Vishnu. The mythical Garuda is staging a
        comeback – only this time in reality. Four years after these endangered birds of the stork
        family started nesting and breeding in Bhagalpur district, their number has increased
        over sixfold – from 78 to over 500.[6] Worldwide its population is about 1200–1300.
        They live in only three places; one is Cambodia and other two are in India. In Cambodia,
        the garuda population is about 150, in Assam the garuda population is about 650,
        and in the Bhagalpur district (around Kadwa Diyara, a place nearby Naugachia)
        the garuda population is about 500.
    </string>
    <string name="setu_name">Vikramshila Setu</string>
    <string name="setu">
        Vikramshila Setu is 5th longest bridge over water in India. The 4.7 km long two lane bridge serves
        as a link between NH 33 and NH 31 running on the opposite sides of the Ganges.
        This bridge has reduced considerably the road travel between Bhagalpur and
        places across the Ganges, like Darjeeling, Siliguri, Assam etc. Before the opening of
        this bridge steamer was being used for transportation across the Ganga river.
    </string>
    <string name="ajgaivinath_name">Ajgaivinath Temple, Sultanganj</string>
    <string name="ajgaivnath">
        Ajgavinath Temple of Sultanganj is one of the ancient Temple constructed on a rock and has wonderful
        collection series of rock sculptures and inscriptions which is historically in the Pala Period.

        Located in the Sultanganj village of Bhagalpur District, this temple is situated close
        to the Holy River Ganga. The origin of this Temple is yet unknown and still a mystery.

        he present name “Ajgaivinath” is connected to Lord Shiva who had given up his bow “Ajgav” at this place and that\’s
        why this historical place came to be known as “Ajgaivinath”.
    </string>


</resources>